Aaron Burzak

Salem, NH, 03079
T: 603.818.1418 E: aaron.j.burzak@gmail.com

Summary

Front-end web developer committed to creating enjoyable and intuitive user experiences. Accomplished in communication and entertainment and recently certified in full stack development through the University of New Hampshire acquiring skills in Javascript, CSS, React.js, and responsive web design. Known for critical thinking, and penchant for design, my goal is to improve myself with each project. Passionate and excited to leverage my skills as part of a team of quality oriented collaborators who share in these ambitions.

Skills

MySQL, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Express, React, React-Bootstrap, Bootstrap, Handlebars, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Heroku, Git, APIs, JSON, Ajax, Python, Django, Microsoft Office Suite, Google Documents, Public Speaking, Communication

Projects

Magic: Trading Block

A platform where collectors of trading cards can advertise, connect, and coordinate trades.

GitHub:https://github.com/MaxFrank13/MtG-Trading-Block

Project:https://immense-garden-06811.herokuapp.com/evaluate

Role: Managed client side development, architect of UI/UX experience

Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript React, React-Bootstrap, MongoDB, Mongoose, Node.js, Socket.IO,

Scryfall API

Trivia-Challenge

A website where users can hone their knowledge with daily trivia challenges and compete for the leaderboard.

GitHub: https://github.com/dpmurphy11/trivia-challenge | Project: https://boiling-reaches-95982.herokuapp.com/

Role: Managed client side development, architect of UI/UX experience

Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Handlebars, Node.js, mySQL, Seguelize, Express,

Axios, TriviaDB API

Cinema Buff

A client side only application that allows fans of cinema to look up movies and their corresponding reviews

GitHub: https://github.com/aguasvivasjc/Cinema-Buff | Project:https://aguasvivasjc.github.io/Cinema-Buff/

Role: Developed the code necessary to integrate and display API calls from the OMDbAPI Tools/Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ¡Query, Foundation, OMDbAPI, NYTimes API

Professional Experience

February 2017 - June 2021

SMS Assist - Chicago, IL

Operations Specialist

- Oversee a nationwide portfolio of single family homes, coordinating efforts necessary to resolve time sensitive maintenance requests while communicating critical updates and expectations.
- Build rapport and relationships with partnered affiliates and instruct them on process
- Develop cultural initiatives channeled through senior leadership and C-Suite while acting as a representative of my colleagues within the SMS Council.
- Produce and implement instructional coaching sessions on standard operations with a focus on the education and empowerment of newly hired employees.

August 2014 - August 2016

Avant - Chicago, IL

Team Lead (Jan 2015 - Aug 2016)

- Lead a team of five to six employees, effectively communicate and train company policy, and delegate responsibilities pending company needs.
- Maintain client accounts through the resolution of escalated and time sensitive issues, and perform final review of financial documents to determine funding of loan applicants.
- Conduct interviews and evaluate potential candidates for employment.
- Audit employee performance and provide weekly feedback to identify areas of improvement

Customer Specialist (Aug 2014 - Jan 2015)

- Verify customer credentials and financial records to expedite and facilitate the application process.
- Receive and resolve a wide spectrum of customer inquiries, requests, and concerns

April 2013 - May 2014

KWC Marketing LLC - Salem, NH

Marketing Associate

- Initiate contact and present offers to potential clientele
- Coordinate appointments and travel for customers

Education

University of New Hampshire

M.E.R.N. Full Stack Web Development

December 2021 - June 2022

Coding Dojo, Chicago, IL

Python Web Development

October 2020 - January 2021 Python

Drexel University, Philadelphia, PA

Bachelor of Science: Music Industry

September 2008- June 2012